So let's start working on the state for actually ordering a burger, right now if we have a look at our
imdi, konteynrlara bir gz atalm u anda bir burger sipari etmek iin devlet hakknda
containers,
pislik yapalm.
we handle that inside our contact data container.
Bunu kontak veri konteynerimizde ele alacaz.
There we have the orderHandler method which is essentially executed when we submit this form we create in
Burada, esas olarak gnderdiimizde emir ileyicisi yntemi var, burada bu konteynerde create formu
this container here, and in this orderHandler we send the HTTP request, we set the state to loading initially
var ve bu sipari ileyicisinde, balangta bir dngy gstermek zere sahne belirlediimiz HTP isteini gnderdikten
to show a spinner then we set it to false once we're done and then we navigate away.
sonra bir kez iki d ayarladk iimiz bitti ve sonra uzaklatk.
We can do all of that in that container,
Btn bunlar o kabn iinde yapabiliriz.
this is not per se wrong or anything like that but we can also outsource it to action creators and
aksiyon yaratclarna ve Rydex'e d kaynak olarak alamayz ve bu sklkla bu sizin iin braklan bir seenektir.
redux and as so often, this is a choice that's left up to you.
Bu yanltr veya byle bir ey deildir, ancak bunu her zaman
But since you in theory could have an application where you also want to be able to submit this request
Fakat siz ve fury, bu istei redux dnyas gibi merkezi bir yere yerletirebilmek iin
from other pages too, maybe putting it into a central place like the redux world is is a good idea,
dier sayfalardan gnderebilmek iin istediiniz bir uygulamaya sahip olabileceiniz iin iyi bir fikirdir.
so that is what we're going to do.
te biz de bunu yapacaz.
We're going to move that submit logic out of this contact data container into an action creator. Speaking
Bu iletiim verileri kapsaycsndan bu deiiklikler iin konuan bir eylem yaratcs iine
of that, for these changes,
mantk gnderme yapacaz.
I want to adjust my structure here
Yapm ayarlamak istiyorum.
in the store folder.
Maaza klasrnde.
I'l create an actions subfolder and I'll create a reducers subfolder and I'll move my actions.js file into
Altria eylemlerin alt klasr ve tm redktrler alt klasr oluturun ve gerek satlar hareketler klasrne atacam
the actions folder and the reducer.js file into the reducers folder and
ve redktr klasrne decek veya sadece decek.
this of course will break the app for now since our import paths will be off.
Elbette, ithalat paralarmz kapatlacandan uygulamay imdilik keseceiz.
I'll also rename the actions file to actionTypes because I want to have a set up shown as at the end
Ayrca, eylemleri sonlandrmak iin eylem trlerine gre yeniden adlandracam nk son modln sonunda olduu
of last module, I want to have an actionTypes file where I simply export these identifiers and then
gibi gsterilmesini ayarlamamz istiyorum. Yalnzca bu tanmlayclar da aktardm eylem trlerini belirtmek istiyorum
I'll create separate files for my different action creators.
ve sonra ayr dosyalar oluturacam farkl aksiyon yaratclarm.
That's actually the first thing I'll do here, I'll add an order.js file here which should hold the action
Aslnda bu ii yapacam ilk ey buydu hepsi bir araya getirdikleri sipari JS'in burada d, bir
creators for submitting an order.
sipari gndermek iin aksiyon yaratclarn tutmas gereken ey.
I also want to create a new reducer file,
Ayrca yeni bir yapmc dosyas oluturmak istiyorum.
I'll name it
Adn vereceim.
order.js too and I'll rename the first reducer to burger builder since it holds code relevant to building
J'yi u ekilde sipari edin ve ilk redksiyondan Burger kurucusuna yeniden adlandracam nk sadece burgeri ina etmekle
the burger only,
alakal kodu tutuyor.
not just the ingredients but in theory to the whole building process
Sadece maddeler deil teori olarak tm yap srecine.
if we were to add more functionalities to it.
Buna gre daha ilevsel olursak.
Again with that, our application will of course be broken.
Yine bununla birlikte, bavurumuz elbette krlacaktr.
I'll also add another file to the actions folder, the burgerBuilder.js file where I want to create
benim uygulama boyunca senkronize eylem Grier'in gerekten gerekli olmad halde burada tutarl bir yaklam.
the action creators for building a burger and there, I'll only have synchronous action creators for adding
Ayrca burger yapmcsnn burger yapm iin eylem yaratclar yaratmak istediim yere dt eylemler
and removing ingredients but still I want to keep that action creator pattern throughout my application
klasrne Rafal ekleyeceim ve katk maddeleri eklemek ve kaldrmak iin sadece
here even though for synchronous action creators, it's not really necessary but it is a consistent approach I'm
ezamanl eylem yaratclar olacam ancak yine de bunu saklamak istiyorum. eylem yaratc
taking here.
desenim burada
So with that, let's start working on all these action creators before we then start implementing the store handling
Bu nedenle, emirler iin d maaza ilemesini uygulamaya balamadan nce tm bu eylem yaratclar zerinde
for orders.
almaya balayalm.